<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-02-05T09:07:07+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Penter Lab</title><subtitle>Understanding cancer and immune cell interactions using large-scale single cell genomics approaches.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">nanoranger released!</title><link href="/2024/01/02/nanoranger.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="nanoranger released!" /><published>2024-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-05T08:52:51+00:00</updated><id>/2024/01/02/nanoranger</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2024/01/02/nanoranger.html"><![CDATA[<p>The new year is starting with great news - nanoranger is seeing the light of day!</p>

<p>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-023-44137-7</p>

<p>This is an approach to perform targeted genotyping of single cell RNA sequencing cDNA 
using Oxford Nanopore.</p>]]></content><author><name>Livius Penter</name></author><category term="publication" /><category term="single cell genomics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The new year is starting with great news - nanoranger is seeing the light of day!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Maylis joining</title><link href="/2023/11/20/Maylis-joining.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Maylis joining" /><published>2023-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-05T08:52:51+00:00</updated><id>/2023/11/20/Maylis%20joining</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/11/20/Maylis-joining.html"><![CDATA[<p>Maylis TOUMI from Agroparistech in France is joining us for her masters studies
in Health Engineering. Maylis will work on distinguishing donor- from recipient-derived
single cells. Welcome Maylis!</p>]]></content><author><name>Livius Penter</name></author><category term="master&apos;s thesis" /><category term="single cell genomics" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maylis TOUMI from Agroparistech in France is joining us for her masters studies in Health Engineering. Maylis will work on distinguishing donor- from recipient-derived single cells. Welcome Maylis!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">PhD position available!</title><link href="/2023/11/15/PHD-Position-available.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PhD position available!" /><published>2023-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-05T08:52:51+00:00</updated><id>/2023/11/15/PHD%20Position%20available</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/11/15/PHD-Position-available.html"><![CDATA[<p>We have two PhD positions available for projects that will focus on interactions 
between leukemia and immune cells. 
In the first project, we will utilize natural genetic barcodes to track leukemia
evolution before and after immunotherapeutic bottlenecks such as allogeneic hematopoietic
stem cell transplantation. 
In the second project, we will long-read sequencing to better understand alternative 
splicing in AML and to use this approach for the identification of novel immunotherapeutic targets.
Looking forward to your application!</p>]]></content><author><name>Livius Penter</name></author><category term="PhD position" /><category term="single cell genomics" /><category term="long-read sequencing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We have two PhD positions available for projects that will focus on interactions between leukemia and immune cells. In the first project, we will utilize natural genetic barcodes to track leukemia evolution before and after immunotherapeutic bottlenecks such as allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation. In the second project, we will long-read sequencing to better understand alternative splicing in AML and to use this approach for the identification of novel immunotherapeutic targets. Looking forward to your application!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Funding from Else Kröner-Fresenius-Stiftung</title><link href="/2023/11/01/EKFS-Funding.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Funding from Else Kröner-Fresenius-Stiftung" /><published>2023-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-05T08:52:51+00:00</updated><id>/2023/11/01/EKFS%20Funding</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/11/01/EKFS-Funding.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are super excited about the news that Else Kröner-Fresenius-Stiftung has decided to 
fund our proposal to use long-read single cell sequencing technologies to identify
novel immunotherapeutic targets in AML/MDS. We’ll soon look for a PhD student who will
work on this exciting project. Stay tuned!</p>]]></content><author><name>Livius Penter</name></author><category term="funding" /><category term="AML" /><category term="long-read sequencing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are super excited about the news that Else Kröner-Fresenius-Stiftung has decided to fund our proposal to use long-read single cell sequencing technologies to identify novel immunotherapeutic targets in AML/MDS. We’ll soon look for a PhD student who will work on this exciting project. Stay tuned!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lena joining</title><link href="/2023/10/01/Lena-starting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lena joining" /><published>2023-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-05T08:52:51+00:00</updated><id>/2023/10/01/Lena%20starting</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/10/01/Lena-starting.html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome Lena in the Penter lab! Lena will work on biobanking, general lab management and the wet lab side.</p>]]></content><author><name>Livius Penter</name></author><category term="team" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome Lena in the Penter lab! Lena will work on biobanking, general lab management and the wet lab side.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Max-Eder Research Group funding from German Cancer Aid foundation (Deutsche Krebshilfe)</title><link href="/2023/10/01/Max-Eder-Research-Funding.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Max-Eder Research Group funding from German Cancer Aid foundation (Deutsche Krebshilfe)" /><published>2023-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-05T08:52:51+00:00</updated><id>/2023/10/01/Max-Eder%20Research%20Funding</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/10/01/Max-Eder-Research-Funding.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are grateful for research funding from the German Cancer Aid Max-Eder Program 
that will provide us with a generous start-up package for the first 4 years. 
Prof. Dr. med. Florian Heidel (Hannover) will serve as mentor for the group - thank you!</p>]]></content><author><name>Livius Penter</name></author><category term="funding" /><category term="digital medicine" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are grateful for research funding from the German Cancer Aid Max-Eder Program that will provide us with a generous start-up package for the first 4 years. Prof. Dr. med. Florian Heidel (Hannover) will serve as mentor for the group - thank you!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Funding from BIH Charité Digital Clinician Scientist Program</title><link href="/2023/05/31/Funding-from-BIH-DCSP.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Funding from BIH Charité Digital Clinician Scientist Program" /><published>2023-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-05T08:52:51+00:00</updated><id>/2023/05/31/Funding-from-BIH%20DCSP</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/05/31/Funding-from-BIH-DCSP.html"><![CDATA[<p>We are grateful for research funding from the BIH Charité Digital Clinician Scientist Program
that will provide Livius with 50% protected research time for a period of 3 years.<br />
A big thank you to Prof. Dr. med. Frederik Damm and Prof. Dr. rer. nat. Nils Blüthgen 
for supporting the application!</p>]]></content><author><name>Livius Penter</name></author><category term="funding" /><category term="digital medicine" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are grateful for research funding from the BIH Charité Digital Clinician Scientist Program that will provide Livius with 50% protected research time for a period of 3 years. A big thank you to Prof. Dr. med. Frederik Damm and Prof. Dr. rer. nat. Nils Blüthgen for supporting the application!]]></summary></entry></feed>